ERIC SAI KIT CHEUNG

FULL STACK DEVELOPER / SOFTWARE ENGINEER

INTRODUCTION

I've owned and operated a food business in Hawaii & Brooklyn, selfpublished a fiction novel, and am now a Full-stack Software Engineer specializing in React & Redux, Javascript, and Ruby & Rails.

I love to build aesthetically pleasing projects, find creative solutions to problems, and am an avid food adventurer and cat instagram follower.

CONTACT

- eric.saikit.cheung@gmail.com
- 646-637-1808
- https://ericskcheung.com/
- n www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sk-cheung
- @ erock_esquire

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FLATIRON SCHOOL

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

February 2020 - June 2020

- Acquired skills for full-stack web development using languages, frameworks & APIs
- React, Redux, Javascript, Ruby, Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, SASS
- AWS S3 Cloud, Google Directions API, Google Geocode API, Geolocation API, Yelp Search API, Leaflet API, React CSS Transition Group, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Material
- Engineered codebase utilizing Geolocation API to acquire users' latitude/longitude coordinates upon login, Google Geocode API to translate coordinates into common addresses, and incorporated Google Directions API by decoding polyline and accessing response object keys.
- Collaborated AWS S3 and Rails Active Storage to hold user images on cloud bucket for convenient access by REST API.
- Designed page layouts with wireframes and Adobe illustrator, and executed page styling using CSS/SASS, implemented custom SVG images and icons into React components, Semantic UI for uniform forms and icons, and Bootstrap & Material for minimalistic page themes.
- Built a Rails backend call to YELP Search API to provide restaurant suggestions at user requested coordinates, and returned response data to be visually rendered on Leaflet API map on frontend.
- Incorporated CSS transition group library to allow transition animations between conditional renders of DOM elements in React. Implemented React-Sortable-Hoc library in combination with Array-Move package to provide user capability of dragging components within DOM.

Notable Projects

CurbAlert - React web app that allows users to see postings of items people are giving or throwing away on an interactive Leaflet map with Google Directions.

Hangouts - React web app that allows friended users to conveniently schedule hangouts at Yelp suggested or searched restaurants at a location calculated to be mutually close to all users.

TV Guidebox – Ruby app that allows users to search for a movie/show from Guidebox API to discover which streaming service (Netflix, Hulu, HBO, Disney+) currently airs the movie/show.

BANZAI PHRESH

SOLE PROPRIETOR / OWNER

April 2016 - June 2018

Honolulu, H

♦ Managed and operated a 6-month pop-up restaurant in Ala Moana Mall, Hawaii. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business. We averaged 100 customers a day, maintained a 30% profit margin, with 4.5 star reviews on Yelp.

Brooklyn, NY

Managed and operated an outdoor food booth for two seasons at Smorgasburg Market, Brooklyn. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business. We averaged 200 customers a day and maintained a 25% profit margin.

KINGS OF FORTUNE

₹

Self-published a fiction novel on Amazon Createspace. Received 5 stars on San Francisco Book Review, 4 of 5 stars on Portland Book Review, and received a featured review on Kirkus magazine.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

FLATIRON SCHOOL

February 2020 - June 2020

2014

BACHELOR OF ARTS

SOKA UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA

August 2008 - May 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React, Redux, Javascript, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL
- NodeJS, Express, MongoDB
- HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Material, Semantic UI